持刀行凶  里克
A stabbing, Rick?
你不觉得平淡乏味吗
Isn't that a little pedestrian for you?
通常你来找我
Usually when you call me,
问的都是如果把头
It's to ask what happens
-放进微波炉会怎样  -这次问的可不是虚构的
- If you put a head in a microwave. - Well, this one's a little less made-up.
死者是我跟的探长的母亲
The victim is the mother of the detective I've been following around.
这案子十年来一直悬而未决
The case has been cold ten years.
我只是觉得
I just figured,
既然你是本市最棒的法医病理专家
Since you're the best forensic pathologist in the city,
也许你能发现什么遗漏的地方
Maybe you could catch something they missed.
要知道现实不是小说
You know reality isn't fiction, right?
你找的可是十年前的凶手
The odds of finding anyone's killer after ten years
我知道这有点天方夜谭
Astronomical, I know.
但如果你愿意帮我看看  我会感激不尽
But I'd appreciate it if you took a look.
好吧  我尽力
Well, I'll do what I can.
但是我不保证有结果
Just don't go making any promises I can't keep.
没问题
Of course not.
-感谢啦  -我尽快给你答复
- Thanks again. - Get back to you as soon as I can.
谢谢
I appreciate it.
死神博士来我家干嘛
What was Dr. Death doing here?
我有点问题要咨询他
Just a little consulting.
我听着好像你在调查
It sounded to me like you were looking into
贝克特探长母亲的谋杀案
Detective Beckett' s mother's murder.
-你总是偷听  -我没有
- Must you always eavesdrop? - I wasn't eavesdropping.
只是碰巧从你办公室门口经过
I happened to walk by your office door.
-而且我住这儿  -是的  我意识到了
- I live here, too, you know. - Yes. I'm aware.
她知道你在查她母亲的案子吗
So does she know you're poking into her mother's case?
还没有新发现  告诉她有什么用
What's the sense in telling her until I find something new?
有没有想过你在侵犯她的隐私
Well, you ever stop to think you're invading her privacy?
又不是偷看她的内衣抽屉
I'm not poking through her underwear drawer.
只是调查她母亲的谋杀案
I'm investigating her mother's murder.
你在开启她尘封的往事  亲爱的
You are digging up her past, darling,
没有经她允许
Without her permission.
现在你要么告诉她  要么放手不管
Now you either tell her or leave it alone.
-天哪  老爸  老爸  -怎么了
- Oh, my gosh, dad! Dad, dad, dad! - What is it?
他邀请我了  他邀请我了
He asked me! Dad, he asked me!
谁邀请你了
Who asked you?
欧文  但我说要问问你
Owen. But I told him I had to ask you.
不过我想你会同意的  对吧
But you'll say yes, right?
因为我已经答应他了
'Cause I told him yes.
-你一定要答应  答应我吧  -答应
- But you have to say yes, so say yes! - Yes?
太好了
Yes!
-我答应什么了  -三四年级生舞会
- What am I saying yes to? - The Junior-Senior Prom.
你又不是三年级生
You are not a junior
-也不读四年级  -没错  但是欧文是三年级生
- Nor a senior. - True, but Owen' s a junior.
欧文  我记得你说他只有15岁
Owen? I thought you said he was only 15.
他跳级了  他好帅啊  老爸
Yeah, he skipped a grade. But he's so cute, dad.
求你了  求你了
Please, please, please.
要是我同意了  能答应我忘记不开心的事
If I say yes, will you promise to stay up, pass your bad time
-玩得开心点呢  -当然
- Have a good time? - Yes!
-别  玩过头了  -老爸  我们只是牵牵手而已
- Not-Not too good a time. - Dad, all we've done is hold hands.
行了  详细情形不要说
Ew, okay, please. Don't need details. Just...
这么说我可以去啦
So I can go?
-当然可以  -我爱死你啦
- Of course you can go. - Oh! I love you.
-我需要一件礼服  -没问题
- Oh! I'm gonna need a dress. - Of course.
一件漂亮的礼服  礼服  礼服
A beautiful dress. A dress, a dress, a dress!
-谢谢  老爸  -你喜欢这个叫欧文的吗
- Thanks, dad! - So do you like this...Owen?
不知道  我没见过他
I don't know. I haven't met him.
你让她和一个你从没见过的人
You are letting her go out with someone
去舞会
That you've never met-
你算什么父亲啊
What kind of a father are you?
我不会帮你调查你女儿的约会对象
I'm not running a background check on your daughter's date.
求你了  她说他很文静
Oh, come on. She says he's quiet,
很内向  而且跟父母一起住
He keeps to himself, and he lives with his parents.
你觉得他会是连环杀手吗
Tell me that doesn't sound like a serial killer to you.
谁是连环杀手
Who's a serial killer?
有人邀请卡塞尔的女儿去参加舞会
Castle' s daughter Alexis got invited to prom.
这是她第一次真正的约会
It's her first real date.
你担心他是个连环杀手吗
And you're worried he's a serial killer?
-你该担心他年少冲动  -他才15岁
- You should be more worried he's a teenage boy. - Ah, he's only 15.
看电视和上网长大的一代
Between satellite TV and the internet,
-15岁相当以前的25岁  -说得对  我也曾15岁过
- 15's the new 25. - Dude's right. I was 15 once.
-现在还是  -如果我有个她这么大的女儿
- Still are. - If I had a daughter her age,
-绝不会让她出门  -谢谢  伙计们
- I'd never let her out of the house. - Thanks, guys.
几小时前  这车因违章停放被拖来
Car was towed in a few hours ago-parking violations.
管理员去查看汽车识别号
When the attendant went to look for the vin number,
发现被害人倒在车里  头部蒙着袋子
He found the vic slumped over with a bag on his head.
六张违停罚单和一张拖车标签
Six parking tickets and a tow sticker,
就没人往车里看一眼吗
And no one bothers to look inside?
车窗贴了膜  挡风玻璃加了遮阳罩
Tinted windows, sunshade on the windshield.
你以为会有人想往里看一看
You'd think someone would try to at least look inside.
纽约欢迎你  知道身份了吗
Yeah, welcome to New York. You got an I.D.?
查到了  乔舒亚·利兹医生  37岁
Yeah, Dr. Joshua Leeds, 37.
根据他钱包里的名片看来
According to the business cards in his wallet,
他是个整容医生
He's a plastic surgeon.
车也是用他的身份登记的
The car is also registered to him as well.
-钱包里有钱吗  -有  几百块
- Any money in the wallet? - Yeah, couple of hundred bucks.
我想可以排除劫杀了
Well, I guess we can rule out robbery.
塑料袋和胶带
A plastic bag and duct tape-
不算是很有效的杀人手段
Not a very efficient way to kill someone.
是啊  但是很有针对性
No, but it's very personal.
行了  通知家人吧
All right, find and notify next of kin.
看看他失踪了多久
Let's see how long he's been missing.
从腐烂的程度看  估计有一周了
From the state of decay, I'd say about a week.
与第一张罚单的时间吻合
That matches the date on the first parking ticket.
初步诊断  死因是窒息
Preliminary cause of death indicates asphyxiation,
但我会做个毒性测验以防出错
But I'll run toxicology just in case.
塑料袋这么薄  为什么不扯破它
That bag's pretty thin. Why wouldn't he just rip it off?
-肯定是被绑住了  -不只是这样
-  He must've been restrained. -  That's only half the story.
他的手指甲被拔掉了
His fingernails were removed.
而且在死之前
And each finger presents signs
每根手指都被折断了
Of having been broken premortem.
折断了
Broken?
如果我没猜错  这医生死前
If I had to guess, I'd say our doctor was tortured
被狠狠的折磨过
Before he was killed.
这是他未婚妻考特妮·莫兰兹
His fiance Courtney Morantz.
一周前报警说他失踪了
She reported him missing a week ago.
-鉴证科在车里有发现吗  -在查指纹  检验纤维
- C.S.U. have any luck with the car? - They're running prints, testing fibers.
明天应该就能拿到结果
We should have results by tomorrow.
好的  谢谢
All right, thanks.
莫兰兹小姐  我是凯特·贝克特
Ms. Morantz, I'm Kate Beckett.
负责你未婚夫凶案的探长
I'm the detective working on your fiance's case..
对于你的遭遇我深感遗憾
I'm very sorry about your loss.
能否占用你一点时间
I was wondering if I could take a moment of your time.
我就知道
I knew it.
他没有回家  我就有预感要出事
When he didn't come home, I just felt it.
你们订婚多久了
How long were you engaged?
快一年了
Almost a year.
本来准备下个月结婚  在花园酒店
We were gonna get married next month, at the Gardens.
凶手要什么  钱吗
What did they want, money?
看上去不像是劫杀
It doesn't appear to be a robbery.
那是为什么
Then why?
乔什有没有做什么事
Was Josh involved in anything that might've brought him
-以至于招来杀身之祸  -没有  乔什不会的
- Into contact with criminal elements? - No. No, not my josh.
他不是这种人
That's just not who he was.
他失踪的那天
On the day he disappeared,
-有发现他有何异常吗  -异常
- Did you notice anything different about him? - Uh, different?
他有没有显得担心  害怕或是心烦意乱
Did he seem worried or scared or distracted?
他很正常
He was fine.
我们约好要见面
I mean, we were gonna meet,
准备一起去尝一尝结婚蛋糕
Because we were gonna go taste some cakes.
结果他没出现  我就打电话到他办公室
When he didn't show, I called the office
他们说他走了  我就打他手机
And they said he'd left, so I called his cell phone,
-但是他没接  -他办公室在市中心
- But he didn't pick up. - If his office was in midtown,
你知不知道
Do you have any idea
-他的车为何停在133号大街  -133号大街
- Why his car would be found on 133rd street? - 133rd street?
他从不往北跑那么远
He'd never go that far north.
他总是走市中心的隧道  再上长岛高速
He always took the midtown tunnel to the L.I.E.
而且要是他迟到了  会打电话告诉我
And if he was gonna be late, he'd call.
他总会打电话给我
He'd always call.
总是让我知道
He'd always let me know.
-查访有收获吗  -没有
- Anything on the canvass? - Nada.
周围居民只记得开罚单之后见过那车
Locals only remember seeing the car after the tickets.
那条街上没有监控摄像头
No security cameras on the street.
未婚妻说的话都属实
Fiance's story checks out.
蛋糕店证实她当时在那里等
Cake shop confirms she was there waiting.
他要去格雷特内克的蛋糕店见未婚妻
Heading to meet his fiance at a cake shop in Great Neck,
怎么就死在了哈林区的街上
How'd he wind up dead on a street in Harlem?
也许他有些秘密连她未婚妻都不知道
Well, maybe he had secrets even his fiance didn't know about.
比如他可能偷偷利用自己的技术
Like maybe he secretly made a living out of
偷走游客的器官
Using his surgeon skills to harvest organs off of tourists
再卖到黑市上
For the black market organ trade.
这素材不错  我要写下来
Whoa, that was a good one. I'm writing that down.
不要像他这样编故事
So instead of making up stories,
我们开始整理时间线吧
We are going to establish a timeline.
什么时候开的第一张罚单
When did he get his first ticket?
-上周三早上  -好  你们去市中心
- Last Wednesday morning. - Okay, so you guys go to the midtown garage
他放车的车库看看  我们去他办公室
Where he kept his car, and we'll hit his office.
-行  -好的
- Cool. - Okay.
问你件事行吗
Hey, can I ask you something?
什么时候你问问题还要求许可了
Since when do you ask permission to ask questions?
是关于你母亲的案子
It's about your mother's case.
你有没有想过  重新开始调查
Have you ever thought about...reopening it?
你想干什么
What are you doing?
-没什么  我是想如果一起调查  -不行
- Nothing. I just thought if we worked together - No.
我有办法
I have resources.
卡塞尔  你要是再敢碰我母亲的案子
Castle, you touch my mom's case,
我们就此结束
And you and I are done.
明白吗
Do you understand?
明白
Okay.
你为什么不想查
Why don't you want to investigate it?
道理一样
Same reason
戒酒了就不再沾
A recovering alcoholic doesn't drink.
你以为我没去过档案室吗
You don't think I haven't been down there?
你不知道
You don't think
我把那份档案的每句话都背下来了吗
I haven't memorized every line in that file?
入警局的头三年
My first three years on the force,
不当班的时候我一直在检查
Every off-Duty moment was spent looking
是否有被忽略的线索
For something someone missed.
我做了一年的心理治疗才明白
It took me a year of therapy to realize
要是我不放手的话  这案子会毁了我
If I didn't let it go, it was gonna destroy me.
所以我放手了
And so I let it go.
对不起
Sorry.
之前我不知道
I didn't know.
是啊  现在你知道了吧
Yeah, well now you do.
就是这里
Well, this must be the place.
男人和胸部是什么关系呢
What is it with men and boobs, anyway?
生理反应  无法克制
It's biological. We can't help it.
难道你没觉得
But doesn't it bother you
那对显然不是真的吗
That they're so obviously not real?
圣诞老人不是真的
Santa's not real.
但是我们都喜欢他的礼物
We still love opening his presents.
他不太可能失踪
It wasn't like him to disappear.
我觉得内心深处我们都知道
I think that, deep down, we all knew that, um,
出事了
That something was wrong.
-他有没有显出焦躁  -没有  跟往常一样
- Did he seem agitated at all? - No, I mean, it was pretty much business as usual.
除了婚礼
Except for the wedding.
我们尽量帮他空出时间让他去度蜜月
We were trying to clear his schedule for the honeymoon.
你们最后一次见到他是什么时候
When was the last time you saw him?
上周二  他正要去见他未婚妻
Last Tuesday. He was on his way to meet his fiance.
什么时候离开办公室
What time did he leave the office?
-大概五点半  -是的
- Around 5:30. - Yeah.
我六点钟打电话给他  还好好的
When I called at 6:00, he was fine.
-他说隧道里堵车  -就是说他离开了曼哈顿
- He said he was in traffic at the tunnel. - He'd left Manhattan then.
为什么又回来呢
Why would he come back?
利兹医生有仇人吗
Did Dr. Leeds have any enemies,
有没有对他的手术导致并发症
Anyone that he had operated on who had had complications
或者失败手术的病人
Or a bad experience?
他的病人从没有过并发症
None of his patients had complications.
那也不能说明病人都开心
That doesn't mean that they were always happy.
整形手术关乎自我形象
Cosmetic surgery is about self-image.
对某些人来说  这能改变他们一生
For some people, it changes their lives.
对于另一些人  怎么做都不够
For others, nothing's ever enough.
有没有病人曾威胁过他
Did any of his patients ever threaten him?
有一个  叫杰西·戈德伯格
One. Jacey Goldberg.
她曾是利兹医生的病人  直到三个月前
She was a patient of Dr. Leeds until about three months ago.
-出什么事了  -她要做面部拉皮手术
- What happened? - She wanted a face-Lift.
-又怎样呢  -她做过三次这种手术
- So? - So she already had three,
利兹医生不愿再给她做
And Dr. Leeds refused to perform the operation.
-那么她怎么办呢  -控告他
- So what'd she do? - She sued him.
当然案子被驳回
It was thrown out of court, of course.
接着恐吓就开始了
That's when the threats started.
至少   以触犯自然法则之名
At the very least, she should be arrested
逮捕她
For violating the laws of nature.
杰茜·戈德伯格的丈夫杰克
Check this out- Jacey Goldberg's husband Jack
一个月前将妻子委托给贝尔维尤
Had her committed to Bellevue a month ago
为她的整容成瘾做精神治疗
For psychiatric treatment for her little obsession.
猜猜谁证明她需要治疗
Guess who testified in support of her commitment?
乔舒亚·利兹医生
Dr. Joshua Leeds.
一个月强制治疗计划
Mandatory 1- month treatment program
她上周出院
She was released last week.
就在医生失踪前3天
3 days before our doctor missing
精神有问题的整形狂人
Mentally unstable plastic surgery chick.
比器官买卖强多了  让她来一趟
That is way better than harvesting organs. Get her in here.
瞧瞧她
Look at her.
-谁会这样作践自己  -没错
- How can anyone do that to themselves?   -Right?
她像是从《冲出人魔岛》逃出生天
It's like she escaped from "the island of Dr. Moreau."
得了  她不是动物  她是个人
Come on, guys, she's not an animal. She's a human being.
我知道  但
Yeah, I know, but...
你认真的  还是引用《象人》[电影主角是畸形人]的台词
Wait, are you being sincere or quoting "the elephant man"?
真粗俗
Oh. Saucy.
戈德伯格夫人  我是贝克特探员
Mrs. Goldberg, I'm detective Beckett.
这是理查德·卡塞尔顾问
This is Richard Castle, a consultant with the department
这是怎么回事  探长
What's this all about, detective?
戈德伯格夫人  你认识一位整容医生
Mrs. Goldberg, are you familiar with a plastic surgeon
乔舒亚·利兹
Named Dr. Joshua Leeds?
是的
Yes.
-你最近起诉他失职  -没错
- You recently sued him for malpractice.   - That's correct.
“拒绝做可选性整容手术
"For refusing to perform elective cosmetic surgery,
"尤其是面部拉皮  植入和抽脂”
"specifically a face-lift, facial implants And liposuction."
我可以保证  每一项都是医学必须的
I can assure you, each procedure was medically necessary.
利兹医生却不这样认为
Dr. Leeds didn't seem to think so.
那自大的混蛋以为自己是上帝
That arrogant bastard thought he can play God
既然这么想整容
Well, if you wanted the surgery so badly,
为什么不整整你的嘴唇
Why didn't you just see another lips?
看其他医生
Doc-doctor.
因为我要最好的医生
Because I wanted the best.
却拒绝给我最好的手术
Who is he to deny me the best?
因此你威胁要毁了他
So you threaten to ruin him
他凭什么替我决定一切
Why does he get to tell me what I can and cannot do?
又凭什么决定我的容貌
Why does he get to decide what I look
这就是你杀他的动机
Is that why you killed him?
-什么  -利兹医生上周被杀了
- What?  - Dr. Leeds was murdered last week.
-谋杀  -就在你精神治疗
- Murdered?   - A couple of days after you were released
出院后的几天
From the psychiatric treatment facility
利兹医生让你去的治疗
That Leeds helped commit you to.
这就是作案动机和时机  顾问
That's motive and opportunity, counselor.
我说过毁了他  不是杀他  区别大着呢
I said I'd ruin him, not kill him. Big difference.
我想你愿意告诉我
Then I suppose you won't mind telling me
上周二晚上去了哪里
Where you were last Tuesday night.
她当时在哪里
So where was she?
她在医院
She was...in the hospital.
-又做整容手术  -没错
- Getting more surgery?   - Yep.
她还剩下什么地方没整
What's she got left to operate on?
-不是吧  -就是
- Oh, no.   - Oh, yes.
认真的  他们还能整成什么样
Seriously? What could they possibly do down there?
明显还有很多
Well, apparently, quite a lot. Ugh.
如果利兹出了名经常拒绝手术
But if Leeds had a reputation of turning people away,
也许他还惹毛过其他人
Maybe there's someone else out there he pissed off.
埃斯波西托和莱恩在检查病人名单
Yeah, Esposito and Ryan are looking through the patient list,
但鉴证组没在车上发现什么线索
But the C.S.U. Came back clean from the car.
普通仇杀不可能
It would be almost impossible for a run-of-the-mill
做的这么干净
Revenge murderer to be that invisible.
-你认为是职业杀手干的  -不知道
- You thinking it's professional?  - I don't know.
戈德伯格夫人有钱雇凶
Mrs. Goldberg had enough money to pay someone to do it,
但她的手术却是完美的不在场证据
Then her surgery is a pretty convenient alibi.
但折磨后闷死  却不像是50岁
But torture and suffocation? That doesn't seem like the work
生活不顺的主妇行事作风
Of a disgruntled trophy wife turning 50.
断指的医生  有人在传递信息
A surgeon with a broken finger says someone sending a message.
怎么样
What do you think?
你很美
You look beautiful.
爸爸  每条裙子你都这样说
Dad, you say that about every dress.
不觉得这显得我很苍白吗
Don't you think this makes my skin look pasty?
甜心  只想让你知道
Sweetheart, I want you to know,
无论你觉得怎样
No matter how you think you look,
你本来就很美
You are perfect exactly the way you are.
一点忙也帮不上
You're not helping.
-天啊  真难看  -谢谢
- Oh, god. No. Hideous.   - Thank you.
试试这条
Here. Try this.
颜色很称你
All right. Good color for you.
-你在做什么  -什么
- What are you doing?   - What?
“真难看”  你想造成她的自我形象问题吗
"you look hideous" Are you trying to give her body-image issues?
真过时  她已经有自我形象问题了
Oh news flash, she already have body-image issue
每个女人都有这样的问题
It's an intrinsic part of being a woman.
世上的每个女人
Every woman in the world
总会讨厌身体的某一部分
Has some part of herself that she absolutely hates.
手太小  脚太大
Her hands are too small, her feet are too big,
头发太直  太卷  耳朵突出来
Her hair's too straight, too curly, her ears stick out,
她的屁股太扁了
Her-oh, god- her butt's too flat,
鼻子太大
Her nose is too big, and, you know,
你所说的  并不能改变我们的感受
Nothing you can say will change how we feel.
男人不明白的是  合身的衣服
What men don't understand is, the right clothes,
合穿的鞋子  得体的妆容
The right shoes, the right makeup just-
很好地遮盖了我们认为难看的瑕疵
It-it hides the flaws we think we have.
让我们觉得自己漂亮
They make us look beautiful to ourselves.
也让他人觉得我们漂亮
That's what makes us look beautiful to others.
曾几何时
Used to be...
让她美丽动人的
All she needed to feel beautiful
是粉色芭蕾舞裙和塑料皇冠
Was a pink tutu and a plastic tiara.
我们穷其一生都想重温这种感觉
We spend our whole lives trying to feel that way again.
觉得怎样
What do you think?
就是你了
I think it's you.
翻看了所有的档案
Staff just went through all the files.
没有危险人物  你查到什么秘密吗
No other red flags. Any dark secrets in here?
有  利兹医生有个弱点
Yeah... Dr. Leeds had a weakness.
能量棒
Energy bars.
他是国际医生协会的自愿者
He volunteered at doctors international,
作公益事业  这家伙是个童子军
Did pro bono work. The guy's a boy scout.
他电脑里甚至没有A片
Hell, he didn't even have any porn on his computer.
真奇怪
That's weird.
没错  知道他上锁抽屉有什么吗
I know. You know what he had in his locked desk drawer?
中文字幕
?? Scotch
支票本  抽屉里锁的是支票本
Checkbook. The guy locked up his checkbook.
-这些文件夹是什么  -婚礼资料
- What about these folders? - Wedding stuff-
礼服订金  酒席发票
Tux deposits, catering invoices.
也许是疯狂的夫妇
Maybe some angry couple killed him
为了婚礼地点才杀了他
For their wedding venue, hmm?
推理的不错
It's as good a theory as any.
这些不全是婚礼资料
These aren't all wedding files.
奇怪
That's odd.
病人的信息都被隐去
All the patient information is blacked out.
也许利兹医生终究有自己的小秘密
Maybe Dr. Leeds has a secret after all.
是他的笔迹  但
It's his handwriting, but...
我从未见过这个档案
I've never seen this file before.
你知道这病人是谁吗
Can you identify that patient?
这里没写
Not from his notes.
只说明是个男性  55岁
Just that it was a male, 55 years old.
这个程序是怎么回事
How about this kind of procedure?
这不可能  我是他的护士长
This is impossible. I'm his primary nurse.
我管理手术小组  没有我他不能做手术
I run his surgical team. He never operates without me.
显然  他做了手术
Apparently, he did.
马里奥  查查利兹医生的日程
Mario, check on Dr. Leeds' calendar.
3月18号的安排
What do you have for march 18th?
他应该去墨西
He... Was supposed to be down at mercy
出席整形外科的专家组会
Attending a panel on reconstructive surgery.
他为什么撒谎
Why would he lie?
没有我  他怎么做了手术
Why would he operate without me?
据医院说  手术进行了9个小时
According to the hospital, the procedure lasted nine hours.
助手和麻醉师都不是医院的人
Neither the assisting nor the anesthesiologist were with the hospital.
都是利兹医生带来的人
Both were brought in by Dr. Leeds.
可也不是他自己的人
Neither of his regulars.
9小时神秘的手术
A 9-hour mystery operation
他不想自己人知道
He didn't want his own people to know about.
医院肯定有病人的记录
The hospital must've had some record of the patient.
医院找不到记录
Get this-the hospital can't find the file.
-好像没发生过一样  -你问的是谁
-It's like it never happened. -Who did you talk to?
-病人资料处  -那你错了
- Patient information. - Well...that was your first mistake.
想在医院里找个病人
If you want to find someone at a hospital who had a treatment there
只有一个部门
There's only one department
什么资料也跑不了
To go to where nothing ever falls through the cracks.
收费处
Billing.
总得有人买单
Someone had to pay for it, right?
谢谢
Thank you.
不  非常感谢
No, I appreciate it.
看来我们神秘病人的账单
Well, it looks like our mystery patient's hospital bills
-已经迅速付清了  -谁付的
- Were paid promptly and in full. -By whom?
电汇  埃斯波西托
Wire transfer. Esposito. Yeah.
-查查这个帐号  -好的
- See what you can find on this account number.  - All right.
-阿丽克西斯挑到礼服了吗  -很可爱
- So did Alexis find a dress yet? - Yeah. A cute one, too.
天  真不敢相信我女儿要参加舞会了
Boy. I can't believe my little girl's going to prom.
我唯一的安慰  是折磨女儿男友的传统
My only comfort now is the long-standing tradition of torturing the boyfriend
什么意思
What do you mean?
当我和他单独相处时
You know, the time-honored hazing that goes on
等我女儿下楼的那一刻
In those few moments we share where he and I are alone
我就可以好好折磨那小子
Just before my daughter descends the stairs.
我记得和我女友老爸见面时的恐惧
I remember the terror of meeting my date's old man.
-他怎么做  -没收我钱包里的套套
- What did he do?   - Checked my wallet for condoms,
向我展示他的手枪收藏
Showed me his gun collection.
我的手抖的厉害  连胸花都戴不好
My hands were shaking so bad, I could barely put corsage on
你爸又怎么做
What'd your dad do?
我不知道  我当时在房里
I... I don't know. I was in my room.
当你出现后  你的男友怎样
How was your date when you finally came out
经你提起  他好像挺害怕的
You know what. Now that you mention it, he looked terrified.
我一直以为他怕我
And this whole time, I thought he was scared of me.
不是  现在到我出手了
Nope. And now it's my turn.
你打算怎么做
What are you planning?
符合我卡塞尔风格的事
Something be fitting name the Castle.
你们一定不会相信的
Yo, you're never gonna believe this.
-发现什么  -猜猜看汇款帐号
-What'd you find?  -That account the money was wired from?
来自美国司法部
It belongs to the U.S. Attorney's office.
不知道是什么手术  是政府买单
Whatever the procedure was, uncle Sam paid for it.
肯定不是隆胸手术
I guess we can rule out boob job.
为什么司法部要为整容手术买单呢
Why would the D.O.J. pay for a cosmetic procedure?
唯一原因  替某人改头换面
There's only one reason- to change someone's identity.
你觉得神秘人是受保护证人
So you think the guy was in witness protection?
利兹医生受折磨而死  凶手要找神秘人
If Dr. Leeds was tortured, I think our killer is trying to find this guy.
那我们要抢先找到他
Then we better find him first.
你怎么找受保护证人
How do you find someone who's in witness protection?
问保护他的人
We ask the people who were protecting him
问“硬糖”  祝你好运
Ask "hard candy"? Good luck.
"硬糖"是谁
Hard-hard candy?
坎迪斯·罗宾逊  联邦助理检察长
Assistant U.S. Attorney Candace Robinson.
让歹徒大哭的人
She makes mobsters cry.
抱歉  探长  但你知道
I'm sorry, detective, but you must know that
受保护证人的资料是绝密的
Information on a protected witness is confidential.
就算你有我们雇佣利兹医生的证据
Whether or not you have proof that we employed Dr. Leeds
也就算你们有动手术的证据
Or whether or not you have proof that an operation to pay
都与我无关
Is irrelevant.
与我的受害人有关
Not to my victim it's not.
与他的家人有关
Not to his family
与他的未婚妻有关
And certainly not to his fiance.
他们打算厮守终生  但已经没有机会
They were planning a life together that they will never have.
我很同情你的处境
Look, I am not unsympathetic to your situation,
但我们都有自己的本职工作
But we all have our jobs to do.
罗宾逊小姐
Ms. Robinson, doesn't it matter to you
你雇的医生被杀了
That the man that you employed was killed
凶手很可能在找你的证人
And whoever murdered him might be looking for your witness?
探长
Detective,
你想我透露的是
You are asking me to expose a witness
一个正在接受联邦调查的证人
During an ongoing federal investigation,
告诉你  这是不可能的
And I am telling you, that is not going to happen.
现在怎么办  这个证人是关键
So what now? This witness of theirs is key.
不知道证人身份
Without knowing who he is
也不知道谁在追杀他
Or who's after him,
无法安排下一步行动
There's no way of getting to the next step.
还有个办法
There's another way
-能确定证人身份  -可以吗  怎么做
- We could figure out who that witness is. - Yeah? How?
坎迪斯·罗宾逊办公室几乎只负责
Candace Robinson's office deals almost exclusively
-有组织罪案  -所以呢
- With organized crime. - So?
如果问问对方呢
So what if we ask the other side?
你想问黑社会谁是证人
You want to ask the mob who the witness is?
他们显然知道他是谁
Clearly, they already know who he is
要不怎么追杀他
If they're trying to kill him.
正如你所言  他肯定是要案的
Like you said, he's got to be a significant witness
-重要证人  -那怎么做  跳上车
- In a pretty big case. - So what do we do, hop in the car,
直接开到巴达冰[电影《黑道家族》中脱衣舞俱乐部]
Drive down to the bada bing?
我认识个家伙  他欠我一个人情
I know a guy. He owes me a favor.
你"认识个家伙"  你以为这是梅特的戏吗
You "know a guy"? What is this, a Mamet play?
德里克·斯道姆年轻的时候
From the early days of Derrick storm.
他就是黑道家族的首领
He's a capo with one of the families.
-其实他人挺好的  -你在说犯罪分子
- He's actually pretty nice. - For a criminal.
我就是说  也许他知道什么呢
I'm just saying, maybe he knows something.
他的料连联邦探员都未必知道
Maybe he can tell us something the feds won't.
我总是忘记你常读戏剧
I keep forgetting you read plays.
我不是坏人  是朋友
I'm-I'm a friend!
是朋友  萨尔
I'm a friend. Sal?
从后面带出去  解决掉
Take him out back. Kill him.
萨尔  你不会
Sal, whoa! Oh! Sal! Whoa, you're go-
是我  哥们儿
It's...it's me, buddy.
等等  维托
Vito! Vito, wait! Vito, wait!
等等  就是给他个警告
Hold up. I was just messing with him.
抱歉  兄弟
Sorry, man.
萨尔  这可不好笑
Not funny, Sal.
说得对  不好笑
Oh, you're right. No, it wasn't funny.
是极度好笑
It was frickin' hilarious!
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard frickin' Castle-
恐怖大师
Master of the macabre. Ha.
什么风把你带来寒舍了
What brings you down off your cloud of money?
谢谢
Thank you.
你说的那家伙
The guy you're talkin' about-
在斯普拉诺家手下做事
He worked for the Spolano family.
老鼠吉米·莫然  是二当家
Jimmy "the rat" Moran. He was an underboss.
老头最器重他  但是
He was a favorite of the old man's, but he got
老头下台后  他被少爷排挤
Squeezed out by junior when the old man bit it.
传闻说几个月前他咸鱼翻身
Rumor has it that he turned state's a few months ago,
斯普拉诺家惊慌失措
And the Spolanos are running scared.
莫然似乎手握装载账单  日历
Apparently, Moran's got it all- Bills of lading, calendars,
账簿  什么都有
Ledgers, the whole shooting match.
足够把老大们都拉下水
Enough to take down all the top guys.
难怪他要改头换面
Well, no wonder he wanted to change his face.
不过  既然他们已经找到了医生
Hey, if they got to the surgeon,
找到他是早晚的问题
It's only a matter of time before they get to him.
-写《斯道姆之警告》时  -爱死那本书了
- When I wrote "Storm Warning" - Oh, I love that book.
谢谢
Thank you.
你说过某些职业杀手
You told me that certain mob hit men
-有标志性的杀人手法或武器  -没错
- Have signature styles or weapons. - That's right.
这个杀手用塑料袋和喉管胶布
Okay, well, this killer used a plastic bag with duct tape
使死者窒息而亡
To suffocate his victim.
听说过这样的杀手吗
Does that sound like anyone you know?
这点你得问斯普拉诺家的人了
You'd have to ask the Spolanos about that one.
不过我觉得他们不会说的
Yeah, I don't think they'd like that.
的确
Heh. Probably not.
-但你肯定认识其他知道答案的人  -谁
- I bet you I know somebody else who might know. - Who?
老鼠吉米
Jimmy the rat.
老鼠吉米·莫然  警方重点对象
Jimmy "the rat" Moran, A.K.A. Jimmy pretty.
他曾涉及赌博  放高利贷
He's been linked to gambling, loan sharking
以及勒索
And extortion schemes.
想要手下忠诚
You know, you want a guy to be loyal,
就不该给他取老鼠这个绰号
You probably shouldn't nickname him "the rat."
我们从斯普拉诺家族
Okay, let's start off by digging up
已知关系人着手调查
All known associates of the Spolano family.
当然  查案时
Yeah, sure, and while we're at it,
我们直接拿头撞墙
We'll just bang our heads against a brick wall,
多好玩
You know, just for fun.
职业杀手根本难以接近
Professional hits are the hardest to close.
因为凶手匿名
Because of the anonymous nature of the murders, the usual rules
从动机和关系着手并不起作用
Like motive and relationship to victim don't apply.
审问莫然  看他知道些什么
We need to talk to Moran. Gotta see what he knows.
何以确信"硬糖"朋友
What makes you think your friend "hard candy"
会和警方合作呢
Is going to cooperate with you now?
你有线人  我也有
You have your sources. I have mine.
是前任男友  对吗
Oh, it's not your ex-boyfriend, is it?
联邦探员  高大爱沉思  冲动武断
Mr. FBI-Tall, brooding and judgmental?
-算是事实  有问题吗  -我没问题
- Why, yes, in fact, it is. Is that a problem? - No. Not for me.
说起来  他又不是来找我复合
But then again, I'm not the one He's trying to get back together with.
真是美妙的惊喜
Well, this is a nice surprise.
是吗  希望这也是美妙的惊喜
Yeah? Hopefully, this is a nice surprise as well.
思缤客[著名蛋糕店]  我真的是一成不变
Sprinkles. Am I really that predictable?
我就是太了解你
Well, maybe I just know you too well.
毕竟我们约会过
I mean, we did date once.
不  谢了  早不吃思缤客了
Oh, no, thanks. I don't eat sprinkles anymore.
也对
Right.
凯特  你这样
So, Kate, is this the part where you
放弃原则  是有案子要我帮忙吗
Ask me to bend the rules to help you on your case?
我太一成不变了吗
Am I really that predictable?
我就是太了解你了
Maybe I just know you too well.
需要我做什么
What do you need?
我想审问吉米·莫然
I wanna talk to Jimmy Moran.
那个黑社会  吉米·莫然
Jimmy Moran the mobster?
为何觉得我能帮得了
What makes you think I can help with that?
联调局和司法部
The FBI and the U.S. Attorney's office
-正对他进行证人保护  -你从何而知
- Have him in witness protection. - And you know this how?
流言蜚语
Word on the street.
就算是真的
Look, even if it's true,
有组织犯罪不在我的职责范围
I don't work organized crime cases.
威尔  你和我都知道是怎么操作
Oh, come on, will, you and I both know how this works.
你去找负责的探员
You reach out to the agent in charge,
他去找负责此案的司法部助理检察官
He talks to the A.U.S.A. Running the case,
-那我就能审吉米·莫然了  -我为何要帮你
- And then I get to talk to Jimmy Moran. - And I do this for you why?
那我这么说好了
All right, let me put this another way.
斯普拉诺家族已经知道
The Spolanos know
吉米在和警方合作
That jimmy is cooperating with the government.
我们知道他们在追杀他
We know that they want him dead
是因为他们杀了你们
Because they murdered the surgeon
雇来帮他整容的医生
You feds hired to change his face.
是你们让医生丧命黄泉
You guys put that doctor in harm's way,
你这么做只为他  而非我
So you're doing it for him, not for me.
是时候了  别紧张
This is it. Don't be nervous.
老爸  别拿假人头吓唬他
Dad! No! No severed heads.
自古就是这种规矩
That's-I- It's time-Honored.
别这样  理查德
No! Richard. .. Really.
别这样  拜托了
Take it off. Come on.
遵命
Fine.
晚上好
Hi.
晚上好  你今晚
Hi. Wow, you look, uh,
美极了
Really nice.
谢谢  你也很帅
Thanks. You, too.
-女儿  看镜头  -老爸
- Baby, find the lens. - Dad.
嘘  假装我不在
Shh. Pretend I'm not here.
爸爸  奶奶 这位是欧文
Uh, dad, gram, this is Owen.
-您好  -很高兴见到你
-Hi.- Delighted.
-您好  -你好  很高兴见面
- Hi. - Hi. A pleasure.
看这对多配  还有花环
Oh, don't they look adorable? And... A corsage.
在这儿  戴在手腕上
Oh, uh, here. It, uh, it goes on your wrist.
好了  谢谢
Oh, okay. Oh, thanks.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
-好了吗  -好了
- Uh, ready? - Yeah.
-好的  -等等等等
- Yeah, okay. - Whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait.
就走了吗  我还没问问
Whoa, that's it? I don't even get a chance to ask him
-他是否杀过人  -爸爸他没有  但我可能有
- If he's killed a man? - Dad, he hasn't, but I might.
好  去吧  别做我想做的事
All right, get outta here. Don't do anything I would do.
再见  玩得开心点
Bye! Enjoy yourselves.
好好玩  再见
Have fun! Good-Bye!
宝贝女儿  真的长大了
My little girl- She's all grown-Up.
是  你们俩至少有一个长大了
Yeah, well, at least one of you is. Uh...
-假人头  -我可是刚开始呢
- A severed head? - Ooh, I was just getting started, too.
我刚准备模仿克里斯·沃肯[著名演员]
I was gonna break into my Chris Walken.
年轻人  告诉我
Whoa. Tell me, little man...
-你是否坐过牢  -很好  很有意思
- Have you ever been to prison? - Very funny, very funny.
不过  亲爱的  演戏还是交给我
But leave the acting to me, honey.
晚上好  贝克特探长
Hi. Detective Beckett.
很高兴你打电话给我  受宠若惊
I'm so glad you called. Regale me.
卡塞尔
Castle?
-模仿克里斯·沃肯  觉得怎么样  -还需磨练
- My Chris Walken. What do you think? - Uh...Needs work.
公平地说  还有部分你得看到
Well, in-In all fairness, part of it's visual.
索伦森答应了  他找了关系
Listen, Sorenson's onboard. He pulled some strings
在司法部找到人帮忙
And got someone at the U.S. Attorney's office to cave.
他要让你审问莫然
He's gonna let you question Moran.
但我们得一小时后出现  你来么
But we gotta be there in an hour. Are you in?
我来不来  教皇信天主教吗
Am I in? Is the pope catholic?
越来越爱你了
It'll grow on you.
说真的  在停车场吗
Seriously, a parking garage?
怎么了
What?
太老套了
It's...pretty cliche.
谁告诉你联调局不老套了
Yeah, well, no one said that the feds were original.
你的下句话就是
Yeah, next thing you'll tell me,
他们停下一辆全黑越野车
They'll be pulling up in a black suburban
车窗贴着反光膜
With tinted windows.
有人把布鲁克海默的
Oh, someone's been watching
电影看多了
Way too many Bruckheimer films.
探长  你只有五分钟
Five minutes, detective. That's all you get.
纽约警局感谢您的合作
The NYPD thanks you for your cooperation.
猴子要我看着吗
Want me to watch the monkey?
-没关系  猴子跟我  -请自便
- That's okay. Monkey comes with me. - Suit yourself.
我爱死你的车了  难以形容的车
Hey, I really like your car. It's very nondescript.
莫然先生  我是贝克特探长
Mr. Moran, I'm detective Beckett.
这位是理查德·卡塞尔
This is Richard Castle.
理查德·卡塞尔  和作家同名
Richard Castle, like the novelist?
-正是在下  -你们不是警察吗
- Exactly like. - I thought you guys were cops.
他是此案的顾问
He's consulting on the case.
我什么都告诉联调局了
Well, look, I already told the feds everything I know.
想要了解斯普拉诺家  问他们
You want info on the Spolanos, ask them.
不过我们找你和斯普拉诺无关
Actually, we're not here about the Spolanos.
是关于帮你做手术的利兹医生
We're here about Dr. Leeds, the man who operated on you.
他怎么了
What about him?
他上周被人杀害了
He was found murdered last week.
被杀  医生被杀
Murdered? The doc was murdered?
窒息而死
Asphyxiated.
头部被用塑料袋蒙住后  贴上喉管胶布
They duct taped a plastic bag over his head.
我们认为斯普拉诺可能与此有关
We believe the Spolanos may have been involved.
可能
"May have been"?
"May have been"?!
鉴于利兹的死法
Given how Leeds was killed
以及你对组织知之甚多
And given your knowledge of the organization,
我们希望你能帮忙确认
We were hoping that you would be able to help identify the-
怎么了
What's wrong?
-让我出去  -我们能帮你  莫然先生
- Get me out of here! - We can help, Mr. Moran.
我们能揪出凶手
We can find the guys who did this,
前提是你告诉我在斯普拉诺家族中
But you have to let me know if there was anyone
谁会这么杀人
In the Spolano family that kills this way.
有  正是我
Yeah, yeah, there is. Me.
喉管胶布  塑料袋  正是我的办事手法
The duct tape, the bag- That was my M.O.
还不明白吗  他们是杀鸡儆猴
Don't you get it? They're sending a message to me,
他们连医生都找到了
And if they got to the doc...
带我回去  现在马上
Take me back! Now!
怎么样
Hey, how'd it go?
觉得彻底失败是什么意思
Oh, do the words "unmitigated disaster" mean anything?
怎么了
What happened?
我们吓到了联邦要案的重要证人
We scared a key witness in a huge federal case
-现在他不愿意作证了  -就这些吗-
So bad that now he won't testify. - Oh, is that all?
贝克特  司法部刚刚打来电话
Beckett. Just got a call from D.O.J.
-长官  你听我解释  -不 是索伦森
- Sir, I can explain - No, no. It's-It's Sorenson.
和莫然回联调局安全屋的路上
On the way back to the FBI safe house with Moran,
有车在他们旁边停下开火
Someone pulled up next to 'em and opened fire.
他和证人坐在后座
He was in the back with the witness.
他们俩都中枪了
They were both been shot.
新款轿车  牌照是车行的
Car was a late-model sedan with dealer plates.
等红灯时  带面罩的匪徒停车
The guy pulls up at a light with a mask on,
打爆车胎  朝车后座开枪
Blew the tires, starts shootin' at the back of the vehicle.
我还以为装的是防弹玻璃
I thought the glass would be bulletproof.
他们用的是警察杀手  特氟龙子弹
They used cop killers- Teflon rounds.
直接穿透车门
Went right through the door.
他还在手术室
He's still in surgery.
不过莫然没事
Moran's gonna be okay, though.
愿意聊聊吗
You want to talk?
没什么好说的  是我促成这事的
There's nothing to talk about. I'm the one who pushed for it,
是我害威尔身陷险境
And I'm the one who got will involved.
你也不没料到会这样的
There's no way you could have known this was gonna happen.
你肯定吗
Are you sure about that?
-他们的车在我们见面后才遭攻击  -所以呢
- Because their vehicle was attacked leaving our meet. - So?
所以有人跟踪了我们
So we were followed.
知晓调查的人
Someone who knew about the investigation
发现了我们的见面
Found out about the meet.
我们把凶手带到莫然跟前  我本该知道的
We led them to Moran. So yeah, I should've known.
如果我是个好警察  我就应该知道
And if I were a better cop, I would've.
你责怪自己吗
You think this is your fault?
没错  是你促成会面
Yeah, you pushed for it,
但你这么做不是为工作  而是因为你在乎
Not because it's your job, but because you care.
多数人遇到拦路虎  会逃之夭夭
Most people come up against a wall, they give up.
你不会
Not you.
你不会退缩
You don't back down.
你可不是普通人
That's what makes you extraordinary.
他会熬过去的  没事的
He's gonna make it. He's gonna be okay.
我
I, uh,
我很开心
I had a good time.
我也是
Me, too.
晚安
Uh... Good night.
Night.
玩得开心吗
Did you have fun?
事实上  是的
As a matter of fact, I did.
约会挺美妙的
This dating thing is kind of nice.
欧文怎么样
How was Owen?
别担心  你们接吻时我闭上眼睛了
Don't worry. I closed my eyes for the kissing part.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
其实你不需要等我的
You know you didn't have to wait up.
分内事儿  等你是为保证你安全归来
That's my job. I wait up. I make sure you're all right.
但是今夜我意识到
But tonight I realized
这份工作我做不了多久了
I'm not going to be doing it for much longer.
-老爸  -过几年  你得离家念大学
- Dad. - A couple years, you're gonna go off to college,
然后结婚  生子
You're gonna get married, you're gonna have kids,
只有假期才能见面了
And I'm only gonna see you on holidays.
除非有小贼偷光我的财产
Until some gold digger steals all my money,
我才能搬去和你同住
But then I get to move in with you.
怎么觉得一下过去了三十年
Wow. I feel like I just lost 30 years of my life.
生活就是这样
That's how it happens.
头一天你还穿芭蕾舞短裙  第二天
One day you're in tutus, and the next day you're...
我都见过你男朋友了
Too old for severed heads.
爸爸  别担心
Dad, don't worry.
不管我会有多老
No matter how old I get,
永远都是你的小小女儿
I'll always be your little girl.
发誓
Promise?
Promise.
谢谢
Thank you.
去睡觉吧
Now go to bed.
好
Okay.
值班同事说她早上四点就来了
Desk officer said she came in at 4:00 this morning.
然后一直在白板前忙活
She's been at the board ever since.
早上六点给我们打电话
She called us in at 6:00 A.M.
重新确认已调查的所有涉案人员
To recheck every person we talked to on the case.
喝了九杯双份浓缩咖啡[一般为男性饮料]
And she's had, like, nine double espressos.
早上好  一直在网上
Hey. Been reading on the internet
看关于"睡觉"这个新事物
About this new thing called "sleep."
睡觉对你会有好处的
Supposed to be real good for ya.
昨晚我对你说的那番话
When I gave you that little speech last night,
可不是让你
I really didn't mean for you
模仿《美丽心灵》
To go all "Beautiful Mind" on me.
肯定不是司法部的人
It wasn't anyone at the U.S. Attorney's office.
他们无需通过我们来找到目标
They wouldn't need us to find him.
那就是我们审问过的人
So it had to be someone that we talked to.
不是因为我找的黑道吗
You don't think it was my mafia connection?
如果他属于那伙人
If he's in a rival family,
他们会希望莫然活着作证
Then they would want Moran alive to testify
因为如果联调局打垮斯普拉诺家族
Because if the feds take down the Spolanos,
其他人就能瓜分他们的地盘
Then the other families can take over their territories.
我们要找的人  在我们介入前
No, we are looking for someone who had access
就能接触到医生
To the doctor before we got the case.
那就是死者的未婚妻和员工
So that leaves the fiance and his staff.
不过未婚妻没有嫌疑
Yeah, except the fiance is clean,
昨晚有不在场证明
Alibied and accounted for last night.
电话记录显示她未和未知号码通话
Phone records don't indicate any calls to unknown numbers.
我想你们肯定也查过职员了
I thought you already ran his staff up.
的确  没有任何记录
We did, and there were no records of anything
-显示他们和犯罪团伙有关   -昨晚呢
- That indicate ties to organized crime. - What about last night?
玛姬·道地和朋友聚餐
Maggie Dowd was at dinner with friends.
马力欧·格雷罗加班整理病人资料
Mario Guerrero worked late packing patient files,
护士长茱莉亚·哈蒙德
And the senior nurse, Julia Hammond,
说她独自一人在家
Claims she was home alone.
马力欧为什么要整理病人资料
What was Mario doing packing patient files last night?
诊所要关门  病人资料要转给
They're closing up shop. Patient files are all going
-新医生  -周五晚上整理资料
- To new doctors. - It's just, doesn't that seem like a weird thing
-不觉得怪异吗  -底层人民的生活
- To be doing on a Friday night? - Yeah, well, when you're low man on the totem pole,
就是这样  领导觉得
That's what life is like. People think they can
周六早上六点也能打电话叫你工作
Call you in to work at 6:00 A.M. On a Saturday.
茱莉亚·哈蒙德和玛姬·道地
Julia Hammond and Maggie Dowd-
在利兹医生手下做多久了
How long did they work for Dr. Leeds?
哈蒙德跟他十年了
Uh, Hammond was with him ten years.
-玛姬是几个月前来的  -怎么了
- Maggie came on a few months back. - Why?
因为我们的底层人民马力欧·格雷罗
Because our low man on the totem pole Mario Guerrero
一个月前才跟的利兹医生
Started working for the doctor about a month ago.
查过他了  还打电话给护校了
We checked him. We even called his nursing school.
-他没问题  -再查一遍  不可能都没问题
- He's clean. - Check again. They can't all be clean.
去哪里
Where are you going?
看看周五晚马力欧是否真在办公室
To see if Mario was actually at the office Friday night.
探长
Detective.
-出什么事了  -马力欧  跟我走一趟
- Is everything okay? - Mario, I need you to come with me.
-为什么  -警方有问题要问你
- Why? - We need to ask you some questions.
我做错了什么
Did I do something wrong?
-贝克特  -是玛姬
- Beckett. - It's Maggie.
-什么  -是玛姬  我们又查了一遍
- What? - Maggie. We double-Checked everything,
而且又给护校打了电话
Even called the nursing schools again.
这次我们让校方发了照片
This time we had 'em send pictures,
玛姬的照片
And the one of Maggie...
和她不是一个人
It's a different girl.
-是玛姬  玛姬·道地人呢  -她今天没来  怎么了
- It's Maggie. Where's Maggie Dowd? - She didn't come in today. Why?
探长
Detective?
利兹医生隶属于圣马革士医院吗
Is Dr. Leeds affiliated with st. Marcus hospital?
-对  在那边办手续  -如果她找到医院
- Yeah. That's where we do our procedures. - If she has a hospital I.D.-
-就能达到目的   -你没事了
- She can finish the job. - You're off the hook...
但别出城
But don't leave town.
这间病房限制进入  请出示身份证
Oh. Room's restricted. Need to see your I.D.
-好的  -名单上有玛姬·道地吗
- Sure. - You have a Maggie Dowd on your list?
在花名册上  让她进来
She's on the roster. You can let her through.
吉米  你可真难找
I gotta say, jimmy, you're a hard man to find.
我花了好几周才发现你整容了
Took me weeks to even find out that you changed your face.
硫喷妥钠  注射死刑用药
Sodium thiopental. It's what they use in lethal injections.
倒是没有塑料袋那么有意思
It's not as much fun as a plastic bag...
但效果相同
But it does the trick.
少爷有话要我转告
Oh, and, uh, I got a message from junior, jimmy.
他说
He says,
去死吧
"Go to hell."
你好
Hi.
你因谋杀利兹医生
You're under arrest for the murder of Dr. Leeds
-以及谋杀吉米·莫然未遂被捕  -太迟了
- And the attempted murder of Jimmy Moran. - You're too late.
天哪
Oh, no. Oh, god.
没事  没连着的
Oh, don't worry. It's not attached to anything.
怎么好像我们知道你要来
It's like we knew you were coming.
谋杀联邦证人未遂
Attempted murder of a federal witness-
-现在怎么判刑  -25年到终生监禁
- What's that going for these days? - 25 to life.
交给你了
She's all yours.
似乎学会了如何
Looks like you managed to set things right with
同司法部合作
The U.S. Attorney's office.
她现在是联邦证人  等莫然康复
She turned state's. When Moran recovers,
联调局就有两名证人指正斯普拉诺家族
The feds will have two witnesses against the Spolanos.
不过玛姬能指证他们谋杀
But only Maggie back there can link them to murder.
她的真名叫做卡拉·但丁
Oh, but her real name is Carla Dante.
他们叫她冷血卡拉
They call her "Carla Coldblood."
她为他们当了五年杀手
She's been killing for the family for five years now.
吉米和警方合作后
When jimmy dropped dime,
斯普拉诺派出了最好的杀手
The Spolanos sent their best.
女杀手  真会打击到女权
Lady hit man-A real blow for women's rights.
真正的玛姬·道地呢
And the real Maggie Dowd?
在西雅图一家医院工作
Works for a hospital in Seattle.
不知道自己身份被盗用
She had no idea that they had stolen her identity.
卡拉甚至成功地
Carla even pulled a recommendation
从求职网站拿到推荐信
Off of a job-Hunting site
才申请了利兹医生手下的职位
In order to apply for the position with Leeds.
起初想找到莫然的照片
Originally she thought she was gonna get a photograph of Moran,
没拿到  就对利兹医生下手了
And when she couldn't, she went after Leeds.
但利兹医生不合作 于是杀了他
And then when Leeds didn't talk, she killed him.
但为何还留下不走
But why stay around the office?
如果在利兹医生尸首被发现前就走
If she left before Leeds' body was found,
自己就有嫌疑了  而且她可能没料到
It would have looked suspicious, and she probably didn't think
尸体一周后才被发现
He'd be sitting around for a week.
我们出现后  她想知道
Then we showed up, and she waited to see
我们的进度
How far we'd get.
做的好  探长  非常好
That's good work, detective. Very good work.
谢谢长官  我从未想过
Thank you, sir. You know, sir, I never thought
自己会说这番话  不过
That I would be saying this, but...
没有卡塞尔  我破不了案
I don't think I could have done it without Castle.
那卡塞尔人呢
Where is Castle, anyway?
原来的法医定性为随机案件
The original M.E. concluded that the stab wounds were random.
但也许是凶手走运  你看此处刀伤
Now maybe the killer got lucky, but you see this wound here?
低角度对准肾脏
It's a low-angle thrust to the kidney.
伤口尺寸显示刀子是有角度的
The wound size indicated that the knife was twisted.
死者当时就休克了
Her body would have gone into immediate shock.
这些呢
What about these?
这些角度显示伤口是在死者
Well, their angles indicate that they were delivered
在地上不动时造成的
After she was immobilized and on the ground.
只是幌子
They're just for show.
这刀是致命伤
This is the one that killed her.
这听着不像意外
This is sounding less like a random killing,
而像蓄意谋杀
More like a targeted murder.
还有呢
There's more.
凭直觉  我查了这位法医的其他资料
On a hunch, I checked the city M.E. Files
求证此案是否是独立的
To see if this was an isolated incident
发现当时有三起持刀杀人案
And found three other stabbings around that time
都被这位法医判为随机案件
That the M.E. Working the case dismissed as... Random.
有关联吗
Were they related?
你真想知道吗
Are you sure you want to know?
你得告诉她
You have to tell her, you know.
你知道她听到会怎样吗
Do you know what this would do to her?
你有了关于她母亲被杀的新情况
You have information that could lead to her mother's killer.
-不能不告诉她  -我知道
- You can't keep that from her. - I know.
可她说如果我调查此案  我们就结束了
But she said if I opened the file, that we'd be through.
有什么关系
It doesn't matter.
别这样
No, you didn't.
别让我发笑了
Stop making me laugh.
得了  你又不是中枪
Oh, come on. It's not like you've been shot or something.
我以为你不再吃思缤客了
I thought you were over sprinkles.
也许还没
Maybe not.
是那个作家猴子
It's the writer monkey.
他还在这里干嘛
What is he still doing here?
书还没写好吗
Haven't you finished your book yet?
最后一张
Last chapter.
能说句话吗
Do you have a sec?
当心  凯特  他喜欢你
Watch it, Kate. He likes you.
你得原谅他  药吃多了
You'll have to forgive him. He is heavily medicated.
怎么这么严肃  没事吧
You look awfully serious. Is everything okay?
坐下
Take a seat.
怎么了
What?
坐下
Sit down.
卡塞尔  怎么了
Castle, what's going on?
是关于你母亲的
It's about your mother.